Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/wolfram-winter-1b69321ab (LinkedIn)

Top-Kenntnisse

Unternehmensleitung Unterrichten Marketing

Wolfram Winter

Founder/CEO Thr3Winters, Professor at Macromedia München

Zusammenfassung

For the past three decades, Wolfram Winter has been one of the leading German media managers. Having obtained a degree in political science, he acquired both journalistic and media-political intuition early on in his studies. Winter wrote his Master thesis on the independence-process of Namibia while staying there. There, he worked as a correspondent and as host for a local radio station. Back in Germany, he worked his way through various radio and TV stations. 1996, he worked as a program director for DF1, a digital Pay-TV platform by the KirchGruppe. Two years later, he became the managing director of Universal Studios Networks, supervising the company's TV activities in German-speaking countries. With his help, Universal was able to put forth six new TV channels. In 2007, working hand in hand with the Premiere AG, Winter founded the Premiere Star GmbH. By then, he was already working as a freelancing entrepreneur. Shortly after, the Premiere Star GmbH found additional support by other shareholders, such as the HypoVereinsbank and Time Warner. During its first business year, the company was able to report a turnover of 120 million Euros. After the company had been taken over completely by the Sky Deutschland AG in 2010, Winter first functioned as senior vice president, overlooking business relations with cable network operators. Later, he ensured the long-lasting success of the payment platform as executive vice president and corporate spokesperson. In 2015, his leadership qualities were honored with the Gold Stevie Award "Executive of the Year in Communications, Investor Relations or PR".

The manager gave his debut as a professor in 2011, sharing his knowledge with the up-and-coming talents of the Macromedia faculty. From 2011 to 2015, he taught in form of a regular professorship. In 2016, he was appointed to teach media management as an honorary professor.

Ever since 2014, Wolfram Winter has furthermore functioned as Chairman of the Media Committee of the Bavarian Economic Advisory Board.

Functioning as managing partner and investor, Wolfram Winter is the CEO of Three Winters, a network founded by him in 2017. The alliance of media experts trains, coaches and advises institutions, executives and eminent figures.

His latest mandates include a role as deputy chairman of the supervisory board for Justt AG - an Al-powered platform for creating, publishing, consuming, sharing and trading quality content on a global scale.

Throughout his work, Winter, can rely on his extensive repertoire of national, as well as international connections.

Berufserfahrung

Justt AG
Deputy Chariman of the Supervisory Board
Juli 2021 - Present (10 Monate)
München, Bayern, Deutschland

LOOPING GROUP
Author MONSIEUR
Januar 2020 - Present (2 Jahre 4 Monate)
Metropolregion München

Three Winters
Founder&CEO
Oktober 2017 - Present (4 Jahre 7 Monate)

As founder and CEO, Wolfram Winter has been pulling the strings at the Three Winters network ever since 2017. The alliance of media experts trains, coaches and advises institutions, executives and eminent figures. Across sectors, trend-setting individuals and companies are led to success through political consulting and a trailblazing PR strategy. With clients such as the Bavarian Red Cross, WDR and the Bavarian International School B.I.S. Being faced with the Corona pandemic, virologist Hendrik Streeck also relies on the communications expert's experience in crisis and PR management.

RareFashion Essentials GmbH
Chairman
Februar 2020 - Present (2 Jahre 3 Monate)
Garching bei München, Bayern, Deutschland

Nayoki GmbH Beirat Juli 2018 - Present (3 Jahre 10 Monate) München, Bayern, Deutschland

Pictures in a Frame GmbH
Chairman
Februar 2018 - Present (4 Jahre 3 Monate)
München, Bayern, Deutschland

Wirtschaftsbeirat Bayern
Chairman of the Committee on Media Policy
November 2014 - Present (7 Jahre 6 Monate)
München, Bayern, Deutschland

Hochschule Macromedia | Macromedia University of Applied Sciences
Professor
April 2011 - Present (11 Jahre 1 Monat)
München, Bayern, Deutschland

knowledge with the up-and-coming talents of the Macromedia faculty. From 2011 to 2015, he taught in form of a regular professorship. In 2016, he was appointed to teach media management as an honorary professor.

Winter describes his work at university as a passion of his. Furthermore, he describes it as an opportunity to decipher the media industry with his students which is characterized by an exhilarating dynamic. For him, this is an

The successful manager gave his debut as a professor in 2011. Sharing his

HORIZONT - Zeitung für Marketing, Werbung und Medien Freelance Writer and Columnist Oktober 2019 - Oktober 2021 (2 Jahre 1 Monat) Frankfurt am Main, Hessen, Deutschland

opportunity to learn from the upbringing generation.

Sky Deutschland AG

Executive Vice President, Communications, Public Affairs and AdSales, Group Spokesman

Dezember 2010 - Juli 2017 (6 Jahre 8 Monate)

München, Bayern, Deutschland

Member of the Executive Management Team, with full responsibility for communications of the M-Dax company, including Corporate Communications,

Consumer Communications, Public Affairs, Internal Communications, Program Communications and Event Communications.

Responsible manager of the Sky management team, overlooking advertising time marketing with a P&L of 80 million Euro, still rising.

Deputy Chairman of the Board of the Sky Foundation.

Sky Media GmbH

Managing Director

August 2015 - Januar 2017 (1 Jahr 6 Monate)

München, Bayern, Deutschland

Republik Namibia Honorary Consul Juli 2005 - Juli 2012 (7 Jahre 1 Monat)

Consular representation of the Republic of Namibia for the federal state of Bavaria.

Premiere Star GmbH

Managing Director and Partner

März 2007 - Dezember 2010 (3 Jahre 10 Monate)

Foundation of the satellite platform Premiere Star, marketing of pay TV channels, establishment of a consortium of shareholders consisting of Premiere AG, UniCredit, Time Warner, EMTV AG, and financial investors, own involvement of 1.4%

Turnover in the first fiscal year over 120 million Euro strongly growing, Ebitda margin of 15%+. Complete takeover by Sky Deutschland AG in 2010.

Sky Deutschland Senior Vice President Distribution Development Januar 2010 - November 2010 (11 Monate) München, Bayern, Deutschland

Developing distribution partnerships with German cable companies (Kabel Deutschland, Unity, etc.), as well as distribution partners in Switzerland and Luxembourg.

NBC UNIVERSAL Global Networks Deutschland GmbH Managing Director August 1998 - Dezember 2006 (8 Jahre 5 Monate) Garching bei München, Bayern, Deutschland Founding Managing Director for German television activities of Universal Studios in the regions of Germany, Austria and Switzerland.

Building of the pay TV channels 13TH Street, Studio Universal and SciFi.

Founding of the free TV channel Das Vierte. Founding of advertising time marketing. Founding of a JV with A&E for the History Channel and member of the board.

Namibian Broadcasting Corporation Editor and Moderator Juni 1988 - Juni 1989 (1 Jahr 1 Monat) Windhuk, Khomas, Namibia

Radio presenter of the morning show, responsible sports editor. At the same time, on-site research for dissertation on Namibia's independence process.

Ausbildung

Ludwig-Maximilians Universität München Magister, Politologie, Psychologie, Sozial- und Wirtschaftsgeschichte · (1985 - 1990)

Bayerische Akademie für Werbung (BAW)

Diplom-Fachwirt für Medienmarketing (1990 - 1991)

Alexander von Humboldt Gymnasium Schweinfurt Abitur (1984)

Rockwall High School High School Diploma · (1981)